# Ruby (Sattar) Romeu – Educator/Software **Engineer/Technical Support Engineer**

Yes, Ruby, like the programming language.

I'm an engineer and a teacher in the Greater Boston Area. Using software development as well as my background in education, my goal is to help others achieve their technical goals and impact the future of tech resources available in underserved communities.





rubysattar@gmail.com

### SOFTWARE EXPERIENCE

## TrueMotion/CMT, Boston - Technical Support Engineer FEB 2021 - PRESENT

At TrueMotion/CMTelematics, we build and maintain the leading smartphone telematics platform. As a TS Engineer, I was responsible for:

- Training and onboarding customers onto the company's program management systems.
- Producing/Maintaining a customer support knowledge base and educational videos.
- Debugging customers' technical issues and documenting the process for internal teams.
- Providing escalated technical and triage support, using an incident response protocol.
- Sustaining Engineering through ongoing releases of configuration changes to the company code base.

## **STEM ENRG, Boston - Project Manager** SEP 2020 - PRESENT

STEM ENRG creates economic equity for women of color in STEM careers. I started as a Mentee and was quickly promoted to Project manager, offering technical support and leading a team through an Agile workflow to develop engineering projects.

## General Assembly, Boston - Engineering Fellow JUNE 2020 - SEP 2020

At GA's Software Engineering Immersive program, I received a holistic technical foundation essential for full-stack development.

- Built full-stack applications for teachers and currently conducting user research for continued iteration.
- Incorporated functionality from 3rd-party APIs to add complexity and nuance.
- Collaborated on teams to build and demo applications in an Agile workflow.
- Problem-solved using industry standard development tools and documentation.

## **PROJECTS**

**Apple HIG Updates Video** — An educational video sponsored by TrueMotion to inform customers about Human Interface Guidelines changes [post-production video editing software used by TrueMotion's Creative Director]

**OverAchiever** — A flashcard learning application [Python, Django, React, Javascript, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, SCSS]

**The Holistic Educator** — A classroom connections tracking application [Mongoose, Express, MongoDB, Javascript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, SCSS]

**Education Donation Store** — *E-Commerce Team project/application* [Mongoose, Express, ReactJS, Javascript, Bootstrap, SCSS1

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

**Javascript** MongoDB **AWS** React **jQuery** Node.js Mongoose Express.js CSS/Scss **Bootstrap DataDog Postman NoSQL** SumoLogic

**RESTful API's** SQL

#### **SKILLS**

**Cross-industry technology Teamwork** Leadership Trouble-shooting Communication Coaching **Project Management** 

#### **EDUCATION**

## LinkedIn Learning — Certificates

NOV 2019

HTML, CSS, SCRUM

Florida International University, Miami -Bachelor's in Elementary Education

MAY 2012 - DECEMBER 2014

Magna Cum Laude, Honors. field research in ed-tech.

## OTHER PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## KIPP Academy, Boston - Kindergarten Lead Teacher FEB 2018 - JUNE 2020

KIPP is a mission-driven school where teachers regularly collaborate to ensure students' academic success.

- Led a DEI workshop for a team of 30+ educators and school leaders, resulting in actionable commitments for the school environment
- Designed a K-8 Women's History curriculum with G-Suite tech resources.
- Utilized Tableau to analyze data and inform instruction
- Implemented differentiated intervention instruction to a top-performing class of 25 families during a global pandemic.

The Mildred (BPS), Boston - Lead Teacher OCT 2017 - FEB 2018

**SFPCC of Harvard,** Boston - *Lead Teacher* AUG 2015 - MAY 2017